

Creative Technologist

+49 174 6231773 minjoolisa.cho@gmail.com <u>Personal Webpage</u> <u>LinkedIn</u>

OBJECTIVE

I am a polymathic creative technologist who designs and implements ideas for connected devices to enhance the experience between users and products, within product networks, and products to the world.

I bring technical concepts that impact human life based on deep affinity to humanity and validate the idea by combining available technical tools.

SKILLS

IoT Development

- Embedded: Arduino, RaspberryPi
- Network protocols: web socket, I2C, Serial, SPI
- Serverless Backend: Firebase, AWS IoT Core, DynamoDB
- Server Backend: Python-Flask, Node.js, JQuery, MongoDB
- Frontend: HTML/CSS, Bootstrap, Processing, P5.js
- · Mobile Native: Android SDK

Emerging Technology

- Machine Learning Libraries:
 Object Recognition, Magenta-Polyphonic RNN
- AR/VR: AR Core, Unity-Vuforia
- Computer Vision Libraries:
 OpenCV, Pygame

Design Tools

- 3D Tools: Rhinoceros, Solidworks, Fusion260, Keyshot
- 2D Tools: Adobe Series (Illustrator, InDesign, Premier Pro)

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Creative Technologist, Indeed Innovation

Hamburg Area, Germany

May, 2017 - Present

<u>Indeed Innovation</u> is an innovation firm implementing a new product or service strategy based on a human-centered design approach. My main roles include:

Fast POC Technical Prototyping for IoT products

- Liaison of developers and designers throughout the conceptual stage of the project and help implementing proof-of-concept prototype to validate the generated ideas.
- Client-facing role: project pitch, design workshop, development progress reports

Interactive Installation development / demonstration

- Full implementation of interactive installation from concept development to delivery
- Concept development, full technical implementation (SW, HW, System integration), demonstration guideline
- On-site/Remote demonstration support: House of Beautiful Business (Lisbon, Portugal), Digital Kindergarden (Germany) etc.

Creative Strategist, Samsung Creative Lab

Suwon, South Korea

Jun 2013 — Oct 2014

<u>Samsung Creative Lab</u> is a Samsung's incubation program for Samsung employees to incubate creative ideas into real project. My role in the team included:

- Proposed the winning idea to gain entry in C-Lab
- Touch Music provides syn-aesthetic music experience to the hearing-impaired people by combining visual and haptic musical experience.
- Product Strategy and development: product features definition, fast-prototyping (Android SW), in charging of user research with the hearing-impaired community
- Regular progress report to the C-level representatives

Product Manager, Samsung Electronics HQ

Suwon, South Korea

Jan 2011 — Dec 2014

My main role as a product manager in the product strategy team in Samsung Mobile division included:

- Responsible for Samsung Galaxy Tablet Series, and Google Nexus 10
- Solving procedural issues during the entire product life cycle development stage to the end of production
- Regular VP/C-level issue reports on the project status
- · Responsible for the communication with the cross functional departments.
- Building a product strategy for the sustainable sales growth, defining USPs for the market communication
- Online communication training for local Samsung branches for the coherent communication messages across the world

LANGUAGES

- English (Fluent, C2)
- Korean (Native)
- Japanese (Fluent, C2)
- Chinese (Intermediate, C1)
- German (Basics, B1)

INTERNSHIPS

Research Intern, ATR (Advanced Telecommunications Research Institute)

Oct 2009 — Feb 2010

Human-Robot Verbal Interaction: Participated in the early development stage of a listener robot for verbal communication with humans, especially in a teleoperation environment.

Research Intern, TOSHIBA R&D Center

Kawaski, Japan

Kyoto, Japan

Aug 2009 — Oct 2009

Human-Robot Nonverbal Interaction: Data visualization of the streaming "Interest Rate" from the robot

EDUCATION

M.S in Industrial Design, KAIST

Daejeon, South Korea

Mar 2015 — Feb 2017

- Mater's thesis: Calm Automaton, A DIY Toolkit for Ambient Displays
- A previous research member of <u>myDesignLAB</u> (Prof. Daniel Saakes)
- · Full year scholarship : National Science and Technology Scholarship

B.S in Electrical Engineering, KAIST

Daejeon, South Korea

Mar 2006 — Feb 2011

- Major in Electrical Engineering and minor in Business Economics
- Full year scholarship: National Science and Technology Scholarship

EXHIBITIONS & PUBLICATIONS

Selfie-metre

Sep 2020

Hebei Design Week, China

An interactive installation that alerts the visitors of their environmental impact based on the carbon footprint of the number of selfies upload to the social media data center.

Brain Composer

Nov 2019

House of Beautiful Business, Portugal

<u>Brain Composer</u> explores the possibility of the brain interface to create Al-driven music application and print it into a 30 note music sheet.

How Will AI Change You

Nov 2017

House of Beautiful Business, Portugal

<u>How will AI Change You</u> provides participants an opportunity to be "A Thinker", reflecting on personal and collective futures with intelligent machines.

Calm Automaton

May 2017

CHI 2017, Denver

<u>Calm Automaton</u> is a customizable and programmable physical display that gently visualizes abstract data in the periphery.

Ratchair : furniture learns to move itself with vibration

Aug 2016

SIGGRAPH 2016, Anaheim

<u>Ratchair</u> is an interface for displacing big objects by attaching relatively small vibration sources.

Minjoo Cho

+49 174 6231773 minjoolisa.cho@gmail.com Personal Webpage LinkedIn

OBJECTIVE

I am a polymathic creative technologist who designs and prototype ideas for connected devices to enhance the experience between users and products, within product networks, and products to the world.

I bring technical concepts that augments human society based on deep affinity to humanity and draw the experience with technical toolkits.

SKILLS

IoT Proof-of-concept prototyping

- · Embedded: Arduino, RaspberryPi
- Network protocols: web socket, I2C, Serial, SPI
- Serverlwess Backend: Firebase, AWS IoT Core, DynamoDB
- Server Backend: Python-Flask, Node. js, JQuery, MongoDB
- Frontend: HTML/CSS, Bootstrap, Processing, P5.js
- Mobile Native: Android SDK

Emerging Technology

- Machine Learning Libraries: Object Recognition, Magenta-Polyphonic RNN
- · AR/VR: AR Core, Unity-Vuforia
- Computer Vision Libraries: OpenCV, Pygame

Design Tools

- 3D Tools: Rhinoceros, Solidworks, Fusion260, Keyshot
- 2D Tools: Adobe Series (Illustrator, InDesign, Premier Pro)

LANGUAGES

- English (Fluent, C2)
- Korean (Native)
- · Japanese (Fluent, C2)
- Chinese (Intermediate, C1)
- German (Basics, B1)

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Creative Technologist, Indeed Innovation

Hamburg, Germany

May, 2017 - Present

<u>Indeed Innovation</u> is an innovation firm implementing a new product or service strategy based on a human-centered design approach. My main roles include: Fast PoC Technical Prototyping for IoT products

- Liaison of developers and designers throughout the conceptual stage of the project and help implementing proof-of-concept prototype to validate the generated ideas.
- Client-facing role: project pitch, design workshop, development progress reports Interactive Installation development / demonstration
- Full implementation of interactive installation from concept development to delivery
- Concept development, full technical implementation (SW, HW, System integration), demonstration guideline

Creative Strategist, Samsung Creative Lab

Suwon, South Korea

Jun 2013 — Oct 2014

<u>Samsung Creative Lab</u> is a Samsung's incubation program for Samsung employees to incubate creative ideas into real project. My role in the team included:

- · Project Proposal: Proposed the winning idea to gain entry in C-Lab
- Product Strategy and development: product features definition, fast-prototyping (Android SW), in charging of user research with the hearing-impaired community
- · Regular progress report to the C-level representatives

Product Manager, Samsung Electronics HQ

Suwon, South Korea

Jan 2011 — Dec 2014

My main role as a product manager in the product strategy team in Samsung Mobile division included:

- Responsible for Samsung Galaxy Tablet Series, and Google Nexus 10
- Product Life Cycle Management: solving procedural issues during the entire product life cycle from the development stage to the end of production
- Regular VP/C-level issue reports on the project status
- Product strategy building for the sustainable sales growth, defining USPs for the market communication

EDUCATION

M.S in Industrial Design, KAIST

Daejeon, South Korea

Mar 2015 — Feb 2017

- · Mater's thesis: Calm Automaton, A DIY Toolkit for Ambient Displays
- A previous research member of <u>myDesignLAB</u> (Prof. Daniel Saakes)
- Full year scholarship: National Science and Technology Scholarship

B.S in Electrical Engineering, KAIST

Daejeon, South Korea

Mar 2006 — Feb 2011

- Major in Electrical Engineering and minor in Business Economics
- Full year scholarship: National Science and Technology Scholarship